

445, Dobong-ro, Dobong-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea

□ (+82) 10-9937-5774 | **>** jqyu.lee@gmail.com | **□** github.com/q00 | **in** linkedin.com/in/q00

"prioritize efficiency while actively avoiding inaction."

Summary.

Current lead backend engineer at start-up company Onuii. 6+ years experience specializing in the baackend development, infrastructure design, and data management. Always try to prioritize efficiency while actively avoiding inaction. My experience is defined with continuous activity and proactive Approach. Interested in ensuring consistency in distributed environment, and learning new technologies about data science.

Work Experience __

Onuii(설탭) Seoul, S.Korea

LEAD BACKEND ENGINEER Mar. 2022 - Now

- Fostered team growth through one-on-one meetings, resulting in an average skill level increase across 14 team members.
- Deployed Kakfa echo system with golang, including consumer proxy, producer, monitoring, to establish an event-driven architecture.
- Implemented a GraphQL gateway for efficient request handling to gRPC services, enhancing endpoint integration and caching. Customizing graphql-mesh, using explicit optional in protobuf3 to handle graphql nullable.
- Designed Data pipeline to make a data lake using AWS EKS,EMR, Trino, Datahub, Spark.
- Provisioned microservice infrastructure using AWS ECS, ECR, and Service Connect discovery, employing IaC tools like Packer and Terraform for seamless deployment.
- Transitioned from monolithic and serverless legacy systems to a microservice architecture using Kafka and gRPC for service discovery.
- · Developed a teacher-student matching algorithm, leveraging AWS Opensearch for data analysis based on sensitive student information.
- Introduced "Risk Search" as a proactive measure in the development process.
- Utilized Post-mortem analyses to create a historical knowledge base for domain-related issues.

Flatgarden Seoul, S.Korea

CTO

- Deployed "입시 고민 메신저 학학이" in App store and google play
- Designed real-time chat bot with Firebase FireStore for scalable service.
- Implemented modified scrum by using zenhub, notion to effectively communicate

Seoul National University of Science and Technology

Seoul, S.Korea May. 2019 - Feb. 2022

Mar. 2020 - Mar. 2022

GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCHER

• Implemented TPC-C Benchmark(WAS, RTE, DB) on IBM DB2 using C, Golang with TTA(Telecommunications Technology Association)

- Developed an Intelligent (AI) Small Water Utility Integrated Management System with Kafka, Telegraf with Kafka Connect, InfluxDB, Grafana with WonJu-si
- Implemented a complete and fast Scraping method for collecting tweets with NSR(National Security Researcher Institute)

Built infrastructure utilizing Docker and Terraform with AWS ECS in AWS architecture and migrated legacy to ecs fargate

Hyundai-Medi Seoul, S.Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Implemented Hospital and Pharmacy Search service using Python Django rest framework.
- Crawled medicine information

Playauto Seoul, S.Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

AUG. 2017 - NOV. 2018

DEC. 2018 - MAR. 2019

- · Implemented data scraping of E-Commerce service like Coupang, G-market for automating registering goods and inventory management
- · Developed an inventory management system for enterprise customer

Education

Seoul National University of Science and Technology

Nowon, S.Korea

M.S. with Database Performance Evaluation, Benchmark

Sep. 2021 - Aug. 2023

Big Data Management and Application Lab, SeoulTech
Research: Concurrency Control, Distributed transaction, Kafka

Seoul National University of Science and Technology

Nowon, S.Korea

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Mar. 2019 - Aug. 2021

DECEMBER 3, 2023 JAEGYU LEE · RESUME

2023	Supporting Distributed Transactions for Elasticsearch based on Two-Phase Commit Dwell Lock, Graduate thesis - Seoul National University of Science and TechNology	Seoul, S.Korea
2022	Data Pipeline for a Real-Time Water Management System with Time Series Prediction Model,	Seoul, S.Korea
	ICESI2022 (International Conference on Electric Vehicle, Smart Grid, and Information Technology 2022)	
2022	TPC-C Benchmarking for ElasticSearch, International Conference on Big Data and Smart Computing	Seoul, S.Korea
	(BIGCOMP)	
2021	A Complete and Fast Scraping Method for Collecting Tweets, International Conference on Big Data and	Seoul, S.Korea
	Creat Computing (DICCOMP)	

Presentation

Papers.

Case studies of building MSA and BI in a distributed environment through AWS ECS, EKS, and EMR

Seoul, S.Korea

AWS Korea Edutech Community Forum 2023

June. 2023

• Edutech Community Form 2023 Detail Page

Smart Computing (BIGCOMP)

- Detail Description in korean
- Presentation Keynote

Implementing a Simple and Easy Chat System in Golang with AWS DynamoDB

Daegu, S.Korea

DEC. 2023

DEVFEST 2023 GOLANG KOREA - GO TO DAEGU

- Hands on about chat system using channel and graphql subscription
- DevFest 2023 Golang Korea Detail Page

Extracurricular Activity

Prography - IT Community Seoul, S.Korea

Aug. 2018 - FEB. 2020 MENTOR

- https://prography.org/
- · Nodejs Mentor

Roubit - routine managing system Seoul, S.Korea

Mar. 2019 - JAN. 2020 LEADER

- Service homepage
- Implemented routine managing service with NFC tags.

Roubit - Routine managing system Seoul, S.Korea

BACKEND ENGINEER Mar. 2019 - JAN. 2020

- Service homepage
- Implemented routine managing service with NFC tags.

PPLE - Blood donation project

Seoul, S.Korea BACKEND ENGINEER Mar. 2019 - JAN. 2020

- Service homepage
- Implemented Direct Blood Donation Process on service.

DECEMBER 3, 2023 JAEGYU LEE · RESUME